Finding Aid for Dekers Blue Line Club records, 1962-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dekers Blue Line Club 1962-2005 1970-2000
Dekers Blue Line Club.
0699 Bimu 2
The Dekers Blue Line Club was formed in 1962 as a booster club for the University of Michigan men's hockey team. It continues to this day with over 750 members. The material contains records relating to the internal functions of the organization, as well as published newsletters, programs, and flyers relating to their activities.
2.5 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (Donor No. 7707 ) was received in multiple accessions.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Dekers Blue Line Club was founded in 1962 with 25 members. The organization is the formal booster club of the University of Michigan men's hockey team and arranges several events annually to raise money, to show support, and to recognize prominent players.
The club has hosted an awards banquet at the close of each year since its inception, to honor team members for excellence. It has also hosted an Old-Timer's Game, a hockey hall of fame, and team reunions during the Old-Timer's weekend since 1980.
The organization has revised their constitution several times and was incorporated in 1984. The organization continues to the present, hosting a variety of activities to raise money, to honor the athletes, and to create a positive environment for the University of Michigan Hockey team.
The records of the Dekers Blue Line Club consist of agendas and minutes of meetings, correspondence, membership lists, and newsletters. These materials document the continuing history of the club since its inception in 1962. When processed in 2006, the accessions were arrayed into two series: General and Publications. The strengths of the Dekers Blue Line Club records resides in its documentation illustrating the club's support of the University of Michigan's Hockey team and the activities celebrating their accomplishments throughout the years.
Subjects:
Dekers Blue Line Club.; University of Michigan--Hockey.; Ice hockey--Michigan.; Inside the Goal Crease
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Dekers Blue Line Club.; University of Michigan--Hockey.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videotapes.
- General
  The General series contains records relating to the functioning of the club. Included in this series are the constitution and bylaws, club correspondence, membership forms and lists, and financial reports. These records are mainly internal in nature and reflect on the yearly continuance of the club. Of interest are the multiple revisions of the constitution and bylaws.
  - Clippings undated (Box 1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws
    - 1962 (Box 1)
    - 1962-Large (Map-case 244, Folder 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1)
    - 1984 (Box 1)
      (Articles of Incorporation)
    - 1985-88 (Box 1)
    - 1999 (Box 1)
    - 2005 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1966-2003, 22 folders (Box 1)
  - Embezzlement Case 1983 (Box 1)
  - Financial Reports 1970-1973, 1982-1997, 16 folders (Box 1)
  - Membership
    - Deker Membership Drive Committee Minutes 1996 (Box 1)
    - Membership Forms 1981-1986, undated (Box 1)
    - Membership Lists 1966-1986, 1989-2004, undated, 30 folders (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia undated (Box 1)
  - Minutes 1966-2005, 38 folders (Box 2)
  - Photographs 1992-1993, undated (Box 2)
  - Player Addresses 1982-1991 (Box 2)
  - Special Events
    - Coaches Luncheon 1982-1983 (Box 2)
    - Parents Weekend 1981-1984, 1990, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Picnic 1990, undated (Box 2)
- Publications
  The Publications series contains printed materials covering the activities and events of the club. Included are programs from the Hockey Awards Banquets, the Blue/White Scrimmage Games, the Old-Timer's Weekends, and newsletters and programs detailing the University of Michigan hockey season. These materials are very informative of the activities sponsored by the Dekers Blue Line Club and also detail the seasons and individuals of the University of Michigan hockey team.
  - Brochures 1991-1997 (Box 2)
  - Calendars 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Flyers 1985-1997, 2000, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Histories
    - Al Renfrew-Michigan's Own, undated (Box 2)
    - 33 Hockey All-Americans and Plenty of Titles, Too, undated (Box 2)
    - Vic Heyliger, undated (Box 2)
  - Hobey Baker Award 1997 (Box 2)
  - Logos undated (Box 2)
  - Alumni Weekend Program 2001 (Box 2)
  - Blue/White Hockey Scrimmage 1990-2006 (Box 2)
  - Dekers Banquet Flyers 1976, 1983, 1985, 1991, 1996, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Dekers Hockey Awards Banquet Programs 1962-2005, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Dekers Banquet Video "Season Highlights" 1999-2000, VHS Tape (Box 2)
  - Dekers Hall of Fame 1990-1996 (Box 2)
  - Dekers Picnic Flyers 1992-2003, undated (Box 2)
  - 50/50 Raffle
    - Annual Report 1994-1996 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence 1993-1995 (Box 2)
    - Gaming Information 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Golf Outing 1985, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Hockey Reunion 1977 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Hockey Reunion Programs
    - 1980 (Box 2)
    - 1985 (Box 2)
    - 1988 (Box 2)
  - Old Timers Game 1989 (Box 2)
  - Old Timers Weekend
    - 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - 1984 (Box 2)
    - 1986 (Box 2)
    - 1991 (Box 2)
    - 1993 (Box 2)
  - Summer Hockey Showcase 2002 (Box 2)
  - Special Events Programs 1988-1996 (Box 2)
  - Stationary undated (Box 2)
  - Newsletters
    - Newsletters, 1970-1974, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - The Dekers, 1975-1977, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Dekers Newsletter, 1978-1985, 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Blue Line News, 1986-1987, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Newsletter, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Inside the Goal Crease, 1989-2008, 21 folders (Box 3)
    - Michigan Hockey Extra 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Newsletters-Electronic (print-outs)
    - Dekers E-News, 2000-2004, 4 folders